A Guide to the Papers of Robert Underwood Johnson, 1885-1925
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Papers of Robert Underwood Johnson 1885-1925
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
7806
12 items.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
This collection was deposited by Clifton Waller Barrett on December 17, 1963, accessioned on January 20, 1965, and changed to a gift on July 1, 1991.
Scope and Content
This collection consists of 12 items, chiefly correspondence of Robert Underwood Johnson.
Arrangement
This collection consists of two series. Series I contains manuscripts, and Series II contains correspondence.
Contents List
- Series I: Manuscripts
  - "Pile high the winter's ..." 1893 August, AQS, 1p.
- Series II: Correspondence
  - Robert Underwood Johnson to W. Rice 1885 March 28, ALS, 1p.
    Sends article by George Rutledge Gibson which he will not use in Century but thinks Rice might want for The North American Review.
  - Robert Underwood Johnson to Samuel L. Clemens 1891 June 8, TLS, 2p.
    Suggests that Twain write a book about his trip abroad ["Mark Twain Abroad") and allow the Century to publish it in serial form.
  - Lathrop [?] to Robert Underwood Johnson 1893 May 3, ALS, 1p.
    Re an article that Lathrop [?] may write about oriental art, mentions Dr. W. S. Bigelow, Ernest Francisco Fenollosa, and Boston Museum of Fine Art.
  - Kate Douglass Wiggin to Robert Underwood Johnson 1904 March 26, ALS, 1p.
    Despite ill health, wants to be in "Fiction Number" and maintain Robert Underwood Johnson's audience.
  - Ethel Brilliana Tweedie to Robert Underwood Johnson 1905 June 20, ALS, 4p.
    Is sending first four chapters of book on Porfirio Diaz, wants it published in an American magazine, describes remainder of book, mentions price.
  - William Merritt Chase to Robert Underwood Johnson 1908 May 11, ALS, 3p.
    Is pleased to hear that Robert Underwood Johnson has accepted his Whistler article, mentions photographs of portraits of and by Whistler, mentions a Keats portrait.
  - Edwin Howland Blackfield to Robert Underwood Johnson 1910 Apr 17, ALS, 1p.
    Thanks for showing of his work in Century.
  - Robert Underwood Johnson to [William Orton Tewson] [(editor of The Literary Review of the Evening Post )] 1924 Nov 27, ALS, 1p.
    Wants to know what has become of a poetic contribution, "ZR and The Roma," which he sent to the Editor.
  - Robert Underwood Johnson to William Orton Tewson 1925 Jan 12, TLS, 1p.
    Thanks for return of poem on dirigibles, is not hostile toward Tewson's conduct of The Literary Review, but prefers traditional poetry rather than current tendencies.
  - Gilbert Parker to Robert Underwood Johnson May 9, ALS, 2p.
    Says that manuscript of a tale of the Straits Settlements, called "Cummer's Son," will be sent to Johnson, asks Johnson to cable if he wants it at $800, is going to Hungary.
  - Jacob August Riis to Robert Underwood Johnson Thursday, ALS, 1p.
    Sends proofs, is excited about illustrations for the article, has arrangd for tickets to be sent to Robert Underwood Johnson.